# CONTACT

Address: 6363 W. Airport Blvd, Houston, Texas



FRANKFURTMACMOSES@ GMAIL.COM



(832) 815 0073



/FRANKFURTMACMOSES



/FRANKFURTMACMOSES

# **SKILLS**

#### **Data Management**

Database Design, Data Quality Assessment, Predictive Analyses, Pattern & Trend identification Data Visualization, Qlik, Tableau, PowerBI, Oracle Apex

#### **Computer Science**

Linux Scripting, R, Python & Java, AWS, Advance Excel, Oracle, Hadoop, Pig, Hive, HBase, Cassandra

### Soft Skill & Management

Project Management, Research design, Communication skills, Problem Solving, Negotiation

# **CERTIFICATION**

- 2020 DASCA Certified Senior Big Data Analyst (SBDA)
- 2020 AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- 2008 Certified Project
  Management Professional
- 2007 Certified Web Component Developer for Java EE Platform
- 2006 Certified Java Programmer

# OLAWOLE FRANKFURT OGUNFUNMINIYI

### PROFILE SUMMARY

Certified Project Manager and Big Data Analyst. With 13+ years of experience in software engineering and data analytics, having exposure in agriculture, telecommunication, finance and public sector. Able to deliver end to end software and data products. Highly educated, possessing Master's and Professional Certifications in data management, software engineering and business operations

## **EXPERIENCE**

DATA ANALYTICS PROJECT MANAGER Bureau of Social Services, Osun State Nigeria September 2012 – December 2019

Project: World Bank Youth Employment and Social Support Operations

- End to end project management to develop strategies, build consensus across cross functional stake-holders and implement recommendations through projects.
- I Identified opportunities for process improvement by tracking and prioritizing numerous forms of data
- I performed in-depth data validation of data collection forms designed by 31 different local councils in to a unified data collection form that appropriately captured data collection objectives of the project within 3weeks as scheduled in the schedule management plan
- My team periodically researched and resolved data discrepancies of collected data. I created dashboard of poor households in the state that was used for disaster palliative distribution decision during crisis caused by insurgents in the country. This reduced double dipping of beneficiaries by 62%. Same data used for distribution of palliative for covid-19 in Nigeria
- I project managed the team that cleaned and merged over 750GB datasets (structured and unstructured data) of poor households in the country with existing World Bank data to determine patterns and trend analyses of poor households in the country
- Myself and my team made presentations on current data management techniques. This included assisting with sentiment analysis and providing technical recommendations for business problems. This increased trust in government policies and intervention by 15%
- We developed poverty baseline metrics through survey and focus group discussion with communities in local councils, and defined data collection and analyses processes that reduced the data collection and analyses processes by 35%, bringing the future investment into data collection, cleaning and analyses process down by 71%

 2006 Oracle Certified Associate

#### MOOC

### **John Hopkins University**

- Data Science Toolbox
- R Programming
- Introduction to Big Data
- Exploratory Data Analysis
- Statistical Inference
- Regression Model
- Reproducible Research
- Practical Machine Learning

# University of California, San Diego

- Introduction to Big Data Analytics
- Hadoop Platform and Application Framework

#### University of Alberta

- Object Oriented Design
- Design Patterns
- Software Architecture
- Service Oriented Architecture

#### DATA ANALYST / QUALITY ASSURANCE MANAGER ChamsSwitch Limited, Nigeria November 2009 – July 2012

**Project**: Internal Revenue Generation and Electronic Payment Gateway (Ivery & Base-24 eps)

- I was involved in cleaning and analyses of financial datasets used for root cause analyses of dwindling revenue generation for state governments that subscribed to collecting revenue platform of ChamsSwitch Limited
- My team created over 300 weekly and monthly reports for payment reconciliation of connected banks and the different state government on the payment platform
- I conducted Hypothesis Test: T-test or Z-test for A/B test to guarantee statistically significant results for different user interfaces of the revenue collection platform. The result was a better user interface that increased usage of our platform over the competitors. Our platform won best revenue collection platform of the year 2010 in Nigeria
- Conducted cluster analysis to identify patterns in income and revenue payments via the collection application
- I worked with management team to prioritize business and information need for the monthly executive meetings

#### JAVA/PLSQL DEVELOPER

MTN, Nigeria June 2008 - October 2009

**Project** Bonus on Incoming Calls

- Directly involved in redesigning of data extraction, transformation and loading pipeline of telecom tariff files into data warehouse, clearing six months backlogs of flat files, loading over 5,000 records of data per minutes in parallel to oracle9i relational database
- Involved in logical modeling and physical modeling of applications with oracle data modeler
- Developed data model, SQL Queries, SQL Query tuning process
- Created SQL\*plus reports as per client's various needs
- Developed SQL scripts for Referential Integrity check, which checks validity of incoming data with master tables in database
- Involved in design and development of business applications using Java/J2EE Technologies

# **EDUCATION**

**Graduate Diploma Computer Science** – Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Nigeria with focused on predictive analysis **Thesis Title**: Comparative analysis of Pig and Hive 2017

**Master of Business Administration (MBA)** - Business School Netherlands specialized in information management

**Thesis Title**: Improving Monitoring and Evaluation System Through Implementation of Big Data and Analytics in Osun State, Nigeria 2015

Bachelor of Science - Obafemi Awolowo University Nigeria 2003